<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

 <properties>
  <title>ThreeTen Backport</title>
  <author>Stephen Colebourne</author>
 </properties>

 <body>

<section name="ThreeTen Backport">
<p>
ThreeTen-Backport provides a backport of the Java SE 8 date-time classes to Java SE 6 and 7.
</p>
<p>
The backport is NOT an implementation of JSR-310, as that would require
jumping through lots of unnecessary hoops.
Instead, this is a simple backport intended to allow users to quickly
use the JSR-310 API on Java SE 6 and 7.
The backport should be referred to using the "ThreeTen" name.
</p>
<p>
ThreeTen-Backport is licensed under the business-friendly <a href="license.html">BSD 3-clause license</a>.
</p>
</section>


<section name="Documentation">
<p>
Various documentation is available:
<ul>
<li>The <a href="apidocs/index.html">Javadoc</a></li>
<li>The <a href="https://github.com/ThreeTen/threetenbp">GitHub</a> source repository</li>
<li>The mechanism to <a href="update-tzdb.html">update</a> the time-zone information</li>
</ul>
</p>
<p>
It should be noted that the API matches that of Java SE 8 except where that is not viable.
Java SE 8 has default and static methods on interfaces which is simulated in the backport
by using an abstract class rather than an interface.
In addition, static query constants are used to simulate method references, for example
use <code>LocalDate.FROM</code> rather than <code>LocalDate::from</code>.
</p>
</section>


<section name="Releases">
<p>
Release 1.1 is the latest release.
It is considered to be stable and usable in production.
</p>
<p>
The project runs on Java SE 6 (or later) and has no dependencies.
</p>
<p>
There are some known issues.
The Hijrah calendar system does not work.
Formatting and parsing often depends on data only available in Java SE 8.
Zone id and text parsing is significantly less powerful.
</p>
<p>
Available in <a href="http://search.maven.org/#artifactdetails|org.threeten|threetenbp|1.1|jar">Maven Central</a>.
</p>
</section>


<section name="Support">
<p>
Support on bugs, library usage or enhancement requests is available on a best efforts basis.
</p>
<p>
To suggest enhancements or contribute, please <a href="https://github.com/ThreeTen/threetenbp">fork the source code</a> on GitHub.
Alternatively, use GitHub <a href="https://github.com/ThreeTen/threetenbp/issues">issues</a>.
</p>
<p>
Note that pull requests and issues will only be considered so far as matching the behaviour of Java SE 8.
Additional requested features will be rejected.
</p>
<p>
<br />
</p>
<p>
<br />
</p>
<p>
<br />
</p>
</section>
</body>
</document>
